Guide to the International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers, Local 361 Records WAG.156
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers, Local 361 Records
1956-2000, 2025-ongoing
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Association of Bridge, Structural, and Ornamental Iron Workers. Local 361 (New York, N.Y.)
Cush, Edward J.
WAG.156
0.25 Linear Feet in one manuscript box.
1 websites in one archived website.
The International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers, Local 361 received its charter on August 6, 1920 to represent ironworkers in New York City. The International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers, Local 361 Records (1956-2000, 2025-ongoing) mostly consist of photographs, articles, and other ephemera related to Local 361's Business Manager Edward J. Cush, as well as the archived website for the union.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Accruals
New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Edward J. Cush, President and Business Manager of the Iron Workers, Local 361, circa 1990. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2001.187 and 2018.020. In 2025, https://ironworkers361.com/ was added through the use of Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession number associated with this website is 2026.015.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Appraisal
Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of ironworkers361.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Scope and Contents
The International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers, Local 361 Records mostly consist of photographs, articles, and other ephemera related to Edward J. Cush, former Business Manager of the Local from 1979-1995. The records contain Cush's column "On the Beam," written for Topping Out, the newsletter for Locals 40, 361, and 417 of the International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers. Other materials in the collection document Cush's retirement in 1995 and his involvement in veteran activities.
The collection also contains materials related to Local 361, such as photographs at building sites, strikes, parades, and other union events; the Local's by-laws; illustrations of the Verrazano-Narrows Bridge; and the archived website of the union. The archived website includes a history of the union; wage and benefit rates; photographs from events; governance information; scholarship descriptions; event listings; and an "in memoriam" page of members who have died since 2001.
Historical Note
International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers, Local 361 received its charter on August 6, 1920 to represent ironworkers in New York City. Throughout its history, Local 361 workers were instrumental in the construction and rehabilitation of bridges and tunnels, stadiums, power stations, airports, colleges, and other buildings in New York City and Long Island.
Iron and steel workers -- Labor unions -- United States.; Building trades -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United States.; Cush, Edward J.
- Archived Website, September 2025-ongoing
- Business Agent Chronology, circa 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- By-Laws, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Clippings, 1951-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "On the Beam" Column, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Photographs, 1956-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photographs -- City College Construction, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Photographs -- Korean War Memorial, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Retirement Correspondence, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Retirement Dinner Program, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Verrazano Bridge Illustrations, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Veteran Event Ephemera, 1991-2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)